我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来
To the outside world,
我只是个普通的鉴证专员
I'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
But secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但当我女儿从未来时空前来帮忙
But when my daughter came back from the future to help,
她改变了现在
she changed the present
现在我们的世界比以往更加危险
and now our world is more dangerous than ever.
我是唯一一个来得及拯救世界的人
And I'm the only one fast enough to save it.
我是闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
乔斯·贾科姆
Meet Joss Jackam.
一个青少年惯犯变成了业余风暴追逐者
She's a delinquent teen turned amateur storm chaser.
那个风向标  看起来非常像
That weathervane, doesn't it look a lot like--
她手里拿的棍子
The staff she was carrying, yeah.
棍子上嵌入了卫星碎片
It's infected with a satellite shard.
卫星不只是创造了新的超能力者
Our satellite didn't just create new metas.
它还创造了超能科技
It created meta-tech.
你每次用震波或者缺口时
Every time you vibe or breach,
暗物质都会影响
the dark matter is going to affect
你的中枢神经系统
your central nervous system,
让你越来越痛苦
causing you more and more pain.
-我们得谈谈  -好的  诺拉
- We need to talk. - Yes, Nora.
没错  我们需要
Yes, we do.
你离开了好久  诺拉
You've been gone a long time, Nora.
你该庆幸我还是回来了
You're lucky I came back at all.
是吗
Really?
我猜你带着很多问题
I can tell you have questions.
请问吧
Ask them.
-你杀了我祖母  -是的
- You killed my grandmother? - I did.
-当着我爸的面  -没错
- In front of my father? - I did.
-他还是个男孩  -诺拉
- He was a boy. - Nora--
他还是个孩子
He was just a kid!
你说得没错
You're right,
每天我都会回想那个瞬间
and I think of that moment every day,
如何改变了命运的轨迹
how it changed the course of destiny
于他
for him,
于你
for you,
于我
for me.
我从未知晓他内心深处怀着那样的仇恨
I never knew he had that kind of hatred inside of him,
都是拜你所赐
but he does because of you.
而我心里对他有着同样的仇恨
And I have that same hatred inside of me for him!
至少曾经是那样
Or at least I did.
我受到他的鼓舞  和你一样
I was inspired by him, as you are.
我想了解他  和你一样
I wanted to know him, as you do.
我想成为他  我想成为闪电侠
I wanted to be him. I wanted to be the Flash.
你永远无法成为闪电侠
You will never be the Flash.
没错
Exactly!
正是这个觉悟  扭曲了我
And that realization is what broke me.
引领着我
That's the realization that led me to do
做出这一切
the things that I did.
糟糕的  可怕的
The terrible, horrible,
邪恶的事情
evil things I did.
我来这里这么长时间了
I've been coming here for so long.
你为什么不坦白你的所作所为
Why didn't you tell me what you did?
我以为你肯定知道
I thought you must know.
你母亲肯定会告诉你
Your mother would've told you.
我错了  现在我知道了
I was wrong. I see that.
我很抱歉  诺拉
I'm sorry, Nora.
我不会再相信你了
I don't trust you anymore.
我已经把一切都给你了
Have I not given you everything?
给你机会回到过去  了解你素未谋面的父亲
The chance to go back and know a father you never knew?
向他学习  和他并肩奔跑
To learn from him? To run with him?
和闪电侠并肩战斗
To run with the Flash.
我教会你如何时间旅行  因为
I showed you how to time travel because...
我想要帮你
I want to help you.
不  你只帮过你自己
No, the only person that you ever help is yourself.
谁说的
Who told you that?
你父亲吗
Your father?
在我的所有记忆里
For as long as I can remember,
我总是只考虑自己
all I ever thought about was myself,
但那将不再是我的污点
and that will not be my legacy.
不再是艾尔伯德·斯旺的污点
That will not the legacy of Eobard Thawne!
让我帮你吧
Let me help you!
我不想要你的帮助
I don't want your help.
再也不想
Not anymore.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第十集
现在既有好消息也有坏消息
So we've got some good news and some bad news.
好消息是中城警局现在仍驻扎在
The good news is that CCPD is still stationed outside
格蕾丝的病房外  等待德怀尔落网
of Grace's room and will remain so until Dwyer's been caught.
但坏消息是
But the bad news is,
这代表德怀尔近期不会再探望她了
that means Dwyer won't be visiting her again anytime soon.
还有更糟的消息
And then the worse news is,
我们对蝉的藏身点一无所知
we have no idea where Cicada could be hiding.
我们不能直接通过匕首的暗能量追踪他吗
Can't we just track him by the dark energy in his dagger?
但只有当他使用时才可以
Well, we can but only when he uses it, which,
所以谢天谢地  目前还没有
thank God, hasn't been recently.
他也没有在面部识别上出现吗
And he's not showing up on facial recognition?
除非他决定现身  否则没戏
Unless he decides to make an appearance, we've got zilch.
这倒是提醒了我  闪电侠小组的其他成员呢
Which reminds me, where the rest of Team Flash is?
长颈鹿宝宝和小诺拉去哪了
Where's baby giraffe and young Nora?
拉尔夫在看望他母亲  有需要可以随时呼他
Ralph's visiting his mom. He said to call if we need him.
-而诺拉在  -我在这
- And Nora is... - Right here.
我顺道去了趟公寓把你的蓝色西装带来了
I just stopped by the loft to pick up your blue suit.
我想你的绿衣也穿够了
I figured you'd had enough of green.
联动时闪电侠与绿箭侠互换身份
可我穿上那件绿衣也不赖
Hey, I made that green suit work, though.
穿这身是要干吗
What is, uh, that for again?
塞西尔妈妈重返法庭的第一天
Mama Cecile's first day back to the courtroom
老爸要针对天气女巫出庭作证
and Dad's testimony against Weather Witch.
乔斯·贾科姆的审判就在今天
Joss Jackam's trial is later today.
半小时后开始
It starts in 30 minutes.
既然我爸正和詹娜一起拜访沃利
Well, since my dad is with Jenna visiting Wally,
我何不与你们一起去支持塞西尔
why don't I come with you guys and help support Cecile?
好啊  他们什么时候回来  顺便问下
Yeah. When are they coming back, by the way?
-他们去了好久了  -他还不确定
- They've been gone forever. - Uh, he's not sure.
自从有个疯子闯进了他的家
After having a psychopath break into his home,
我想他应该不急
I don't think he's in any rush
把一个新生儿带回中城
to bring a newborn back to Central City.
此外  塞西尔重返岗位的第一天
Besides, Cecile has a lot on her plate
肯定有很多事要忙
with this being her first day back at work.
我等不及要看到天气女巫
I can't wait to see Weather Witch
罪有应得的那一刻了
get what she deserves.
你准备好从手中取出那些碎片了吗
Hey, you ready to get those shards out of your hands?
当然
Hell yes!
我有几个礼拜都没能好好玩四公主了
I haven't been able to play PS4 properly for weeks.
里面等你
See you in there.
你感受到了吗
Hey, you feel that?
感受到什么
Feel what?
是自由时光的感觉
That's the feeling of free time.
就是律师免费的时间
AKA unbillable hours,
所以  你在接下来的这段时间
so we better not be seeing any invoices from you
别再让我们干什么活儿了
in the near future.
没问题
Oh, that's all right.
这个谜题我免费为你们解开
This is one mystery I will solve for free.
被告人乔斯琳·贾科姆
The state versus Joslyn Jackam,
中城刑事法庭  超能力犯罪99512号案件
Criminal Court of Central City, meta-crime number 99512.
欢迎回到我的审判室  霍尔顿女士
Welcome back to my courtroom, Miss Horton.
你的产假过得还愉快吧
I trust your maternity leave was enjoyable?
多谢关心  法官大人
Thank you, Your Honor.
我很高兴能够回到工作中来
I am very happy to be back at work.
跟孩子待多长时间都不算多  不是吗
Yeah, there never really is enough time with a newborn, is there?
是的  你可以开始了
There is not. You may proceed.
谢谢  法官阁下
Thank you, Your Honor.
这次起诉的目的是为了证明
The prosecution intends to prove
在11月20日至27日间
that between November 20th and 27th,
乔斯琳·贾科姆利用这个装置
Joslyn Jackam used this device,
一种被称为超能力科技的装置
a so-called piece of meta-tech,
非法地  并且是有意地
to unlawfully and intentionally
伤害了中城的居民
harm the citizens of Central City.
她的超能力犯罪还包括
Her meta-crimes include
对铁山监狱造成了巨大的财产损失
massive property damage at Iron Heights,
使谢尔顿县机场的21架飞机被迫停飞
the grounding of 21 separate flights at Sheldon County Airport,
还有针对她的父亲马克·马登的
and the attempted murder of her own father,
杀人未遂
Mark Mardon.
这场针对他父亲的袭击是
Now, this attack on her father was--
这
Uh, the--
这场针对她父亲的袭击是有预谋的
the attack on her father was premeditated.
还有
Um, and...
这场起诉是为了...
the prosecution is seeking the--
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事  就是
Yeah, it's just a...
感觉
feeling.
我没事的
I'll be fine.
控方希望判处最高刑期  法官大人
The prosecution is seeking the maximum sentence, Your Honor.
夹到了
Gotcha.
好  快好了
All right, almost done.
微尺度手术可不简单
Micro-scale surgery is not the easiest.
所以第一次的时候你才没发现这些
Is that why you missed these the first time?
闭嘴吧
Hey, now!
好了  结束了
All right, there you go.
你的手里终于没有匕首碎片了
Your hands are officially dagger shard free.
感谢上帝
Hallelu.
还有一件事
One more thing.
超能力缝合对超能力伤口
Mm, meta-sutures for meta-wounds,
聪明
that's clever.
得记下来  冰疗愈真的好疼啊
Ah! Note to self, ice healing actually hurts.
别当个胆小鬼
Don't be a wuss.
胆小鬼  你才是胆小鬼
Wuss. You're the wuss.
看来你已经完全掌握
Looks like you've got this whole
凯特琳和冰霜杀手共存模式了
Caitlyn/Killer Frost thing down pat.
-还没完全掌握  -我来吧
-  Eh, not totally. -I got it.
但是转向冰霜杀手模式的确轻易了些
But it is getting easier to switch to Killer Frost
当我需要的时候
when I need to.
在伤口痊愈后  缝合处应该会保持冰冻状态
So those sutures should stay frozen while the wound heals.
一旦它们融化了  你就可以把绷带解了
Once they melt, you can take the bandages off.
到时候你就没事了
You'll be good to go.
我必须得承认
I have to confess.
我最近真的很享受没有超能力的时光
I've actually really enjoyed not having my powers lately.
-真的  -对
- Really? - Yeah.
我再次习惯了成为没有震波能力的西斯科
I got used to being Cisco again sans Vibe-age, you know?
而且没有每周一次的恶徒们威胁到我
And not having villains breathing down my neck
我必须得说  感觉太棒了
once a week, I have to say, is pretty schway.
如果我们想要打败蝉的话
Well, if we're gonna defeat Cicada,
我们就需要完全恢复的震波
we need a fully functioning Vibe.
所以希望这个有效吧
So hopefully this does the trick.
给你  纪念品
Here, souvenirs.
-非常感谢  -不客气
- Oh, thank you so much. - You're welcome.
在针对乔斯的审判法庭上
Opening statements are underway
开场陈述进行得并不如人意
in the trial of Joss Jackam,
乔斯又被称为天气女巫
otherwise known as Weather Witch.
在午餐的时候喝三四杯马蒂尼又没关系
Just saying, nothing wrong with three or four martinis at lunch.
如果你开车的话就有关系了
It is when you get in your Lamborghini and drive.
先生  专注点
Sir, sir, focus here.
碰自己的鼻子
Touch your nose.
那是我的车
Hey! That's my car!
然后发生了什么  佩利特女士
And then what happened, Miss Pellett?
她制造了一个带着闪电的龙卷风
She created some kind of lightning tornado.
我还以为我们都要死了
I wasn't sure if any of us were gonna make it.
我得走了
I got to go.
请稍等一下
One moment, please.
我得走了  出现了一起偷车事件
I got to go. There's been a car theft.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你可是我重要的犯罪现场证人
You're my lead CSI witness.
你三十分钟后就要上证人席了
You're on the stand in 30 minutes.
抱歉  那是辆兰博基尼
I'm sorry. It's a Lamborghini, all right?
警车是没办法追上那玩意的
The cops aren't gonna be able to keep up with this thing.
-很快的  -就三十分钟
- It'll be quick. - 30 minutes.
-好  -霍顿女士
- All right. - Miss Horton?
我们刚才说到哪了
Hmm, where were we?
各位  那辆车在第八街向北开了
Guys, the car just turned north on 8th,
-朝着韦克菲尔德方向  -收到
- headed towards Wakefield. - Got it.
准备好控制车子
Get ready to take control of the wheel.
-你打算怎么做  -制服司机
- What are you gonna do? - Get the driver.
来了
Here we go.
爸
Dad!
-发生了什么  -我没法停止振动
- What's happening? - I can't stop vibrating.
-各位  我们需要你的帮助  -各位
- Guys! We need your help! - Guys!
-帮什么  -帮
- With what? - With--
帮这个
With that?
我没法停止穿越
I can't stop phasing.
我没法一直抵消他的穿越
And I can't counter-phase him forever.
这可不太妙
Okay, that's not good.
如果你持续  而你不继续
If you keep going but you don't,
那你就会
then you could...
迎接你的死亡
fall to your death.
-对啊  -我们要怎么办
- Yeah! - What are we gonna do?
让他穿
Let him.
什么
What?
是的  如果你穿过这层地板
Yes, if you phase through the floor,
你会掉进管道牢房里
you're actually gonna fall into pipeline cell
在我们正下方
directly below us.
而能力抑制组件会抵消你的超能力
And the dampening unit will negate your powers.
除非我们没卡好时间
Unless we don't time it right.
那样的话  你进入监狱的时候
In which case, your torso would be severed from your legs
身体和腿脚就会分离
as you enter the cell.
-你这是帮倒忙  -停下  停下
- Not helping. - Stop, stop.
好了  停  我相信你  西斯科
Okay, stop. I tr--I trust you Cisco.
向右边走
Move to the right.
不  是我的右边
No, my right.
西斯科  别这样
Cisco! Come on!
好了  就在那里
Okay, stop right there!
-后退一步  -西斯科
- One step back. - Cisco!
实际上  别了  往前一步
Actually, never mind, one step forward.
准备好了吗  三  二  一  走
Okay, ready? Three, two, one, go!
能力阻尼器开启
我这是怎么了
What's going on with me?
是这样
So...
你碰到的那辆车
the car you touched
充满了不稳定的暗物质
was saturated with unstable dark matter.
因为你那时候正在穿越
And because you were phasing at the time,
所以导致了你整个身体
it caused your body to destabilize
在细胞层面失去稳定性
on a cellular level.
当我接近驾驶员的时候
When I got close to the driver,
我看到暗物质纹理出现
I saw dark matter veins flare up,
就像是斯宾塞·扬的手机上的一样
just like on the back of Spencer Young's phone.
所以那辆车是件超能科技
So the car is a piece of meta-tech?
或者是控制它的东西
That or whatever was controlling it.
他要在里边呆多久
How long is he gonna have to stay in there for?
没有能力阻尼器的帮助
Without the help of the power dampeners,
可能需要一天的时间
it could take up to a day?
不行不行  我还要在大概十分钟后
No, no, no, no! I-I have to present evidence on the stand
上庭去作证
in, like, ten minutes.
塞西尔会杀了我的
Cecile's gonna kill me.
这可不好
That's not good.
我可以去
I could do it.
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
当爸爸让我成为正式员工时
Well, when Dad made me official,
他把我的资料送交到了法庭
he submitted my paperwork to the court,
所以我有资格出庭作证
so I'm qualified to present forensic evidence.
我可以的
I can do this.
真不敢相信我第一天回来就遇到这事
I cannot believe this is happening on my first day back.
我的第一天啊  好吧
It's my first day back. Okay.
去法院书记官那里  做登记
Go to the court reporter. Check in.
告诉他巴里是遇到了  车祸
Tell her that Barry was in a traffic accident.
是
Yes.
还有  诺拉  当你上庭之后
And, Nora, when you're up there on the stand,
跟随我的指令就好
you just follow my lead.
明白了吗
Got it?
别担心  诺拉没问题的
Don't worry. Nora can handle this.
不是这事
It's not that.
我决定要提出较轻的判决
I've decided I'm gonna pursue a lighter sentence.
你为什么突然变心了
Why the change of heart?
因为我不断地感觉到
Because I keep feeling these
乔斯散发着悔恨
waves of remorse coming off of Joss.
我想她只是想重新开始
I think she just wants to start over
以免变成她父亲那样
so she doesn't turn out like her father.
闪电龙卷风
那么  韦斯特小姐  你能解释下
So, Miss West, can you explain what effect
这些情况对谢尔登县机场造成的影响吗
these conditions had on the Sheldon County Airport?
设施被大风袭击
The facility was hit by winds
240到400千米每时的大风
ranging from 150 to 250 miles per hour.
那还真是挺危险的
Wow, that's-that is pretty dangerous.
但是  却没有一个人受伤
And yet not a single person was injured.
没有  但那是因为...
Well, no, but that was because--
那跑道上的这些闪电痕迹呢
What about these lightning marks on the tarmac?
能不能说这些在
Would you say that that is common,
那样的天气环境下
given the nature of the weather
是很常见的呢
during the incident in question?
没错  幸运的是  在这个案子里
Yes, but luckily, in this case,
闪电只击到了跑道
the lightning only hit the runway
而不是周围的建筑
and not the surrounding structures.
乘客都在那些建筑里
The structures where all of the passengers were.
要我说  这可是真的非常幸运
I would say that is pretty lucky indeed.
法官大人  公诉人说完了
Your Honor, the prosecution rests.
这就完了  你不问我别的了吗
So that's it? You're not gonna ask me anything else?
看起来如此
Well, it would appear so.
李先生  该你了
Mr. Lee, I think you're up.
韦斯特小姐  我的当事人是超能力者吗
Miss West, is my client a meta-human?
不是  但是她用了超能科技
No, but she used meta-tech.
具体说是天气杖
Specifically a weather staff
被暗物质侵染了
that was corrupted by dark matter.
所以可以说是这支杖  而不是我的当事人
So one could say it was the staff, not my client,
在那天晚上袭击了谢尔登县机场
that attacked the Sheldon County Airport that night?
不  缺一不可  是她使用了那支杖
No, one couldn't. She used that staff.
但这不就是一个普通的天气杖
But isn't this just an ordinary weather staff
被暗物质侵染了吗
corrupted by dark matter?
这是你说的
These are your words.
是的  但是...
Yes, but--
既然暗物质可以侵染工具
And since dark matter was able to corrupt a tool
将它变成大规模毁灭性武器
and turn it into a weapon of destruction,
有没有可能它也侵染了被告呢
isn't it also possible it could corrupt the defendant?
不  暗物质不会让你做出什么事
No. Dark matter doesn't make you do things.
她将闪电引向了机库  里面满是恐惧的人们
She pointed lightning at a hangar full of scared families.
法官大人  那机库里可还是有小孩子
Your Honor, there were little kids in that hangar.
你知不知道  闪电的热度要比
Did you know that--that lightning is five times hotter
太阳表面高五倍
than the surface of the sun?
这就是被告释放到人群上的
That is the kind of power that the defendant unleashed
力量强度
upon those people.
是她做的
She did this.
这是她的选择  不能信任她
This was her choice, and she can't be trusted.
不  韦斯特小姐  请你坐下
No, Miss West, you must sit down.
我知道  但是法官大人...
I know, but, Your Honor--
-坐下  -不  她说得对
- Sit down! - No! She's right.
我有罪
I'm guilty,
我应该为我的行为付出代价
and I should pay for what I did.
-你在做什么  -看一看这个
- What you doing? - Get a load of this.
你记得你移除的那些碎片吗
You know those shards you removed?
我对它们进行了生物分析
I ran a biochemical analysis on them
对比了我手上的组织
and the tissue from my hands.
你知道怎么做吗
You know how to do that?
我这些年跟着医学博士凯特琳·斯诺
I picked up a thing or two from Caitlin Snow MD
学到了一些  然后我发现了这个
over the years, and I found this.
这是我刚被划伤时候的组织样本
That's my tissue right after I got sliced.
这是今天的
That's from today.
几乎所有暗物质都消失了
Almost all the dark matter is gone.
那碎片并没有抑制我的超能力
The shards weren't dampening my powers.
而是在移除他们
They were removing them.
所以那个匕首有抵抗暗物质的特性
So the dagger has anti-dark matter properties.
是的
Yes!
西斯科  如果我们能把它合成血清
Cisco, if we can synthesize that into a serum,
我们就能彻底摆脱蝉的超能力了
we could get rid of Cicada's powers entirely.
不仅是他的  所有人的
And not just his powers, everyone's.
-所有人  -凯特琳
- Everyone's? - Caitlyn,
我们能做治愈超能力者的解药
we could make a meta-human cure.
你觉得我们需要治愈超能力者的解药
You think we need a meta-human cure?
你不觉得吗
Don't you?
好吧  可能不觉得
Okay, maybe not.
但我怎么记得你之前想要摆脱超能力
But I seem to remember a time when you did?
没错  我第一次发现冰霜杀手时
Sure, when I first discovered Killer Frost,
我想摆脱她
I wanted to get rid of her.
但她消失时就好像我身体的一部分缺失了
But when she was gone, it felt like a piece of me was missing.
而且我们也见过超能力者
Besides, we have seen meta-human powers
做了好事啊
do really good things.
没错  如果你能建座冰桥
Okay, yeah! If you can build an ice bridge
避免交通拥挤的话
to avoid rush hour traffic,
但如果我的存在让我周边的人
but what if my existence gives everyone around me
像游戏里那样都辐射中毒呢
radiation poisoning like "Fallout"?
那些超能力者
Those metas,
我们违背他们的意愿创造了他们
we created them against their will.
不  斯旺创造了粒子加速器
No, Thawne created the particle accelerator
并且破坏了它
and he sabotaged it.
那谁击碎了全是暗物质的卫星
And who shattered the satellite full of dark matter
创造了数不清的超能力者
and created God knows how many metas?
是我们
We did that.
这种解药能够给超能力者
This cure could give meta-humans a second chance
一个回到正常生活的机会
at having a normal life.
不是所有人都想要正常生活  西斯科
Maybe not everyone wants a normal life, Cisco.
小心
Watch out!
她以为她是谁啊
Who does this lady think she is?
搞什么
What the hell?
你是谁
Who are you?
来接你的  走吧
Your ride. Let's go.
乔斯·贾科姆根本就没到铁山监狱
So Joss Jackam never made it to Iron Heights.
没  运输司机说
Nope, and the transport driver said
那个带走她的女人
that the woman who took her used something
用某种东西让他的卡车抛锚了
that completely shut down his truck.
停
Pause.
那个  眼熟不
That. Look familiar?
又是卫星碎片
Ugh, another piece of satellite shard.
所以那东西也是超能科技
So the fob is the meta-tech?
没错  或许发出某种暗物质脉冲
Yeah, probably sends out some kind of dark matter pulse
能在短时间内重写任何制导系统
that overrides any guidance system in seconds.
所以只要她有发动机
So as long as she has an engine,
她就能控制它
she can control it and
而我们还不知道要找的人是谁
we still don't even know who we're looking for.
或许我们知道  能快进吗
Maybe we do. Hey, can you fast-forward?
停
Stop.
看  那个敬礼  她一定是军人
Yeah, look, that salute. She's definitely military.
在国防部数据库里匹配这个面孔
Okay, let's run that face through the DOD database.
发现匹配项
拉娅·范赞特
Raya Van Zandt.
前空军王牌飞行员  机修工
Former air force, ace pilot, mechanic,
车辆组装方面的专家
and expert in vehicle operations.
她被开除军籍了
She was dishonorably discharged.
她的呼号是“银色魅影”
Call sign was Silver Ghost. Huh?
她的其他服役记录被封存了
The rest of her military record was sealed.
我看我爸能不能找到人帮忙
Okay, well, I'm gonna see if my dad can call in a favor
或许我们能拿到副本
and maybe we can get a copy.
同时  看来我们
Yeah, and in the meantime,
要追踪两个坏女孩
it looks like we have two bad girls to track down.
我不确定  诺拉
I'm not so sure, Nora.
塞西尔说她能感受到乔斯的悔意
I mean, Cecile said that she could feel Joss' remorse.
得了  妈妈  那是在作秀
Come on, Mom. That was a show.
你觉得这次逃跑是巧合吗
I mean, do you think this escape was a coincidence?
我们还不清楚  诺拉
Uh, well, we don't know yet, Nora.
不  我们清楚
Yes, we do.
拉娅拿着那东西把乔斯从监狱车里劫跑
Raya got that fob to break Joss out of the prison transport.
我敢说乔斯也知情
I guarantee you Joss is a part of this.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
因为坏人是不会改变的
Because bad people don't change.
各位  有没有办法弄点吃的下来
Hey, guys, any way you could send down some food?
欢迎来到大本营
Welcome to home base.
什么大本营
Home base of what?
年轻无赖帮
The Young Rogues.
管理这座城市的老家伙们太多了
There's been enough old men running this town.
该我们了
Our turn.
我有几位候选人
I have my eyes on a few candidates,
但这项工作  计划就你和我来做
but for this job, plan on it just being you and me.
我没计划做任何事
Um, I'm not planning anything!
我连你是谁都不知道  把我送回去
I don't even know who you are! Just take me back!
间谍区域
你听过天眼会吗
You ever heard of A.R.G.U.S.?
是用最前沿的科技构造的离网设施
It's an off-the-grid facility primed with bleeding-edge tech,
被地球上最先进的
and it's protected
安全系统保护着
by one of the most advanced security systems on Earth.
唯一能使其短路的是
The only thing that can short it out is
十亿电流
a billion jolts of electricity.
所以就是几道闪电
So a few bolts of lightning.
你是天气女巫对吧
You're the Weather Witch, right?
这个墙下是该设施的电力枢纽
Beneath this wall is the facility's power junction.
你击中它  我们就有四分钟的时间
You hit that and we have a four-minute window
来获得让我们势不可挡的东西
to get something that will make us unstoppable.
不  听着  我不会帮你的
No, look, even if I was gonna help you,
就算我要帮
and I'm not,
我也需要我的天气设备来控制
I need my weather staff to control any of that,
而那些现在全在警察手中
and right now, that is in police holdup.
所以还是请你送我回去吧
So if you could just take me back.
好
Okay.
回去做什么
To do what?
自首
Turn myself in.
我明白
I see.
你不想像你父亲一样
You don't want to be like your dad.
我理解  但已经太晚了
I get that, but it's too late.
你是个罪犯  我也是
You're a criminal. So am I.
外面那些人
And those people out there,
相信我  他们想的都是"有其父必有其女"
trust me, all they think is, "Like father, like daughter."
但我想你需要自己明白这点
But I guess you need to find that out for yourself,
是不是
don't you?
需要的时候来找我
Find me when you do.
谢谢
Thank you.
这能支撑你到出去
That will hold you until you get out--oh!
我能问你个问题吗
Uh, can I ask you a question?
你有时间吗
Uh, do you have a minute?
有
Yeah.
是的  你哪里都去不了
Yes, you're not going anywhere.
去年你从神速力里出来
So, um, last year, you came out of the Speed Force
你一直在写一种符号语言
and you were writing a kind of a symbol language.
你还记得吗
Do you remember that?
我记得
Yeah, I remember.
显然西斯科只能翻译其中的一句话
And apparently, Cisco could only translate one of these phrases.
是吧
Right?
目前是这样  连吉迪恩也做不到
So far, yeah. I mean, Gideon couldn't even do it.
吉迪恩
Gideon.
对  吉迪恩
Right, Gideon.
所以你觉得那种语言是什么
So what do you think that language was?
我不知道  它是某种时间语言学
I don't know. It was some kind of, uh, chronolinguistics.
你在神速力里得到的时间语言学
Chronolinguistics that you got from your time in the Speed Force,
同时显示了所有时间  是吧
which is all time at once, right?
过去  现在  未来
Past, present, future.
你觉得这种语言是什么  或许是未来吗
What do you think this language was? Future, maybe?
为什么  这和蝉有关吗
Why? Is this about Cicada?
蝉  不不不  只是...
Cicada? No, no. No, It's just, um...
谜题  是吧
le mystère, huh?
我是个侦探  我看什么都是谜题  所以
I'm a detective. I see mystery everywhere, so...
好吧  谢谢
all right. Thank you.
下次见
See you next time.
好的  趁我还没忘
Okay--oh! Ah, before I forget,
传奇们留下了一些书
the Legends, uh, dropped off some, um, books
帮你打发时间
to help you pass the time.
"解禁的欲望"
"Uncaged Desire."
你那种被囚禁的欲望
Your kind of caged desire.
希望你喜欢
Hope you enjoy it.
-下次见  -谢谢
- See you next time. - Thanks.
是啊  可能不是很好
Yeah, probably not very good.
再见
See you!
怎么了
What is it?
根据多普勒  中城里起了飓风
According to Doppler, it's a hurricane in Central City.
不  这不是飓风  是乔斯
No, it's not a hurricane. It's Joss.
检测到恶劣天气
我来搞定
I'm on it.
什么  闪电侠今天不来吗
What, no Flash today?
他觉得不必来阻止一场假飓风
Figured he wasn't needed to stop a fake hurricane.
我们可以在你的简历上
Guess we can add damaging private property
加上破坏私人财产这一项
to your résumé.
听着  我需要你的帮助
Look, I just need your help.
别演这种烂戏了
Oh, stop with the sorry act.
你朋友帮你逃走的时候就完了
That ended when your friend helped you escape.
她不是我的同伙  我也没有逃走
She is not my buddy, and I did not escape.
听着
Look,
我想回去自首
I want to turn myself back in.
你真的指望我相信吗
Oh, you really expect me to believe that?
我爸爸是职业罪犯
My dad is the career criminal,
我不是
not me.
我只是...
I just...
我想向所有人证明
I want to show everybody
我不是他们以为的那种人
that I'm not the person that they think I am.
那你需要我做什么
Then what do you need me for?
你是个英雄
You're a hero.
如果你为我担保
If you vouch for me,
人们会知道我说的是实话
people will know that I'm telling the truth.
听着  我会告诉你一切
Look, I will tell you everything.
我甚至会告诉你那个女人带我去了哪里
I'll even show you where that woman took me.
只要给我一个机会
Just give me a chance.
如果有人问起来  就说你从没见过这个
If anyone asks, you never saw this.
谢谢你  摩根少校
Thank you, Major Morgan.
请告诉中将
Please tell the lieutenant general
我爸爸和我欠他一个人情
that my dad and I owe him one.
特快专递  一个天气女巫
Special delivery. One Weather Witch.
什么  我以为你要帮我
What? I thought you were gonna help me.
我努力要自首
I'm trying to turn myself in.
不  我没逃跑  我被绑架了
No, I-I didn't escape. I-I was kidnapped.
你能告诉他们吗
Will you please tell them?
对不起  我不相信罪犯
Sorry, I don't trust criminals.
她是你们的了
She's all yours.
不不不  这是个误会
No! No, no! This is a misunderstanding!
这不公平
This is unfair!
我要和她谈谈  拜托了
If I could just talk to her, please!
你父亲也会做同样的事
Your father does the exact same thing.
当有事情困扰他时  他就会跑起来
When something's on his mind, he runs.
我没有困扰  妈妈
Nothing's on my mind, Mom.
我要看看拉娅·范赞特的国防部档案
I got to take a look at Raya Van Zandt's DOD file.
你发现了她和乔斯
Oh, yeah, did you find the connection
之间的联系吗
between her and Joss?
好像并没有什么联系
Well, there doesn't seem to be one.
真的吗
Really?
是的  她在一次海外任务失败后
Yeah, she left the air force
离开了空军
after a failed mission overseas,
又做了两个月办公室工作
and then she spent two months on desk duty,
然后被开除军籍了
and then she was dishonorably discharged.
但她的服役记录好像挺好的
But it seems like she has a pretty good service record.
没错  很明显国防部丢了脸
Exactly, so clearly the DOD had egg on its face
拉娅成了替罪羊
and Raya became its scapegoat.
我想说  诺拉
I'm just saying, Nora,
并不是每个人都像他们看起来那么坏
not everyone is as bad as they seem.
拉娅  乔斯  每个人都值得第二次机会
Raya, Joss. I think everyone deserves a second chance.
如果你不相信我  去问你爸爸
If you don't believe me, ask your father.
他给别人的第二次机会是我见过最多的
He gives more second chances than anyone I've ever met.
加油  加油
Come on. Come on.
好  好  好
Yes. Yes! Yes, yes, yes!
太好了
Yes!
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
我在从蝉的匕首碎片里
Well, I was distilling dark matter ore
提取暗物质矿石
from Cicada's dagger shards.
但我不能再这么做了  是吗
But I can't really do that anymore, can I?
哎哟
Whoops.
你为什么要这么做
Why did you do that?
你很聪明  你能搞清楚的
You're smart. You can figure it out.
你什么时候才能搞清楚
When are you gonna figure out that
超能力治疗其实可以帮助人们
a meta-cure could actually help people?
听着  我都听过了  很简单
Listen, I heard all about it, short stuff.
但你知道吗  凯特琳和我
But you know what? Caity and I,
我们现在状态正好
we're doing just fine,
你也一样  直到你满脑子都是蝉
and so were you until Cicada got all up in your head.
别这么做  这不仅仅是关于我
Don't do that. This isn't just about me.
不是个屁
Oh, the hell it isn't!
你知道吗  我懂了
And--and you know what? I get it.
他想杀了你
He tried to kill you.
你想发明出能救我们所有人的东西
You're trying to create something that'll save us all.
对  我是
Yeah, I am!
我们所有人
All of us!
巴里  爱瑞丝  诺拉  他们是个家庭
Barry, Iris, Nora, they have a family.
甚至你和凯特琳也组成了奇怪的小家庭
Even you and Caitlyn have your weird little family.
但是我的家庭呢
But what about my family?
我想要可以与之白头偕老的妻子
I want a wife to grow old with.
我想要孩子
I want a kid.
而且我不想让他们时刻都要担心
And I don't want them to wonder all the time
他们的爸爸是不是有麻烦
if their dad is in trouble,
他今晚能不能回家
if he's even gonna make it home tonight.
西斯科  你不需要在拥有超能力
Cisco, you don't have to choose between having powers
和家庭之间做选择
and having a family.
是吗  有的人需要
Yeah? Well, some of us do.
我不是闪电侠
I'm not the Flash.
我不想成为闪电侠
I don't want to be the Flash.
我想做我自己
I want to be me.
解药是唯一的方法
A cure is the only way.
或者说曾经是
Or it was.
什么
What?
拜托
Oh, come on, girl.
你在读米克的书吗
You're reading Mick's book?
这本书
This is...
写得特别好
surprisingly well-written.
怎么了
What's going on?
只是很难相信有些人会改变
Just having a hard time believing some people can change.
为什么
How come?
经历了这一切之后
'Cause after everything that you've seen,
你不认为坏人会一直很坏吗
don't you think that bad people stay bad?
并不总是这样
Not always.
我第一次见莱昂纳多·史纳特时  他是罪犯
When I first met Leonard Snart, he was a criminal.
可能是全城最坏的罪犯
Probably the worst criminal in the city.
但是我
But I--
我知道
you know, I knew
他心中有好的一面
that there was a good person in there somewhere,
看看他
and look at him.
他成了一名传奇
Turned out to be a Legend.
成了烈士
Died a hero.
如果他可以改变  那么任何人都可以
If he can change, anyone can.
你真的相信这一点吗
You really believe that?
我相信
Yeah. I do.
那艾尔伯德·斯旺呢
What about Eobard Thawne?
我认为
I think...
成为英雄的一部分
part of being a hero
就是要能够看到人们心中好的一面
is being able to see the good in people.
也许未来的某一天
So yeah, maybe someday in the future...
即使是斯旺也能够改变
even Thawne could change.
再说了  如果连我们都不相信人们
Besides, if we don't believe in people,
又有谁会相信呢
who will?
真好笑
Very funny!
车辆失控
I got 595s!
我们这里有很多车  快走
We got a lot of vehicles! Let's go.
收到  换上装备
Copy that. Suit up!
我们的停车场出现大量失控车辆
We've got multiple 595s in our own parking lot!
快出去
Get out there quick!
请求更多支援  这里有很多车
Requesting more backup! We've got a lot!
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
做其他人不会为你做的事
Doing what no one else is gonna do for you...
给你第二次机会
Offer you a second chance...
天气女巫
Weather Witch.
就是那里
That's it.
电力枢纽就在那里
That's where the power junction is.
用上你所有的力量
Give it everything you got.
-这到底是怎么回事  -我不知道  长官
- What the hell was that? - I don't know, sir.
但是它破坏了41到60的安全电网
But it knocked out security grids 41 through 60.
耗时十年  投入两千四百万美元
Ten years and $24 million later,
隐形汽车  又称SAM  终于问世
the stealth automobile, AKA the SAM, was born.
有传言说  罩在这下面的一切
Rumor has it that everything under its hood
都直接来自韦恩科技
comes directly from WayneTech.
这是一辆两千四百万美元的原型车
This is a $24-million prototype?
它能做什么
What can it do?
我们来试试看吧
Let's find out.
天眼会
是乔斯还是拉娅
Is it Joss or Raya?
我猜是她们两个  因为有人刚刚
I'm guessing both because someone just stole
在一次精准的闪电袭击之后
a very expensive vehicle from A.R.G.U.S.
偷走了天眼会一辆很贵的车
after a very precise lightning strike.
是一辆具有各种功能的
It's a next-gen prototype
新一代原型车
with all the bells and whistles.
这些花里胡哨的功能会爆炸还能杀人
If bells and whistles could explode and murder people.
而且恐怕无法追踪
And supposedly it's untrackable.
我们要怎样找到它
So how do we find it?
-我们不搜索那辆车  -我们搜索她们
- We don't search for the car. - We search for them.
如果乔斯又发起了闪电袭击
If Joss made lightning strike again,
也就是说她拿到了权杖
it means she has her staff.
我们可以追踪它里面的暗物质  太棒了
Oh, so we can track the dark matter in it. Nice!
我找到位置了
I got the location.
车辆
记住  诺拉  不管做什么
Okay, remember, Nora, whatever you do,
都不要在使用超能力时碰到那辆车
don't touch the car while using your powers.
凯特琳  可以跟我过来一下吗
Hey, Caitlin, can I steal you for a second?
兜风结束了  银色幽灵
Joyride's over, Silver Ghost.
乔斯  我需要和你谈谈
Joss, I need to talk to you.
坚决拒绝
Hard pass.
我爱远程引爆
Got to love remote detonation.
前方道路结冰
Icy roads ahead.
天啊  拉娅
Oh, my God. Raya!
拉娅
Raya!
穿越
我的天啊
Holy Buckaroo Banzai.
信号丢失
它能穿过去
It phases?
她们刚刚用的穿越把戏
Whatever phase-trick they just used,
干扰了我们的追踪
it jammed our tracking.
如果她不用天气权杖
We can't get a lock on them
我们就无法定位到她们
if she doesn't use that weather staff.
XS会来追我们的
XS is gonna come after us.
让她试试吧
Let her try.
非礼勿听  非礼勿视
Hear no evil, see no evil.
我们现在隐形了
We're invisible.
西斯科
Hey, Cisco?
你可以把我连接到那辆车的通信系统吗
Can you connect me to the car's comm system?
不行  但是我可以让你发出无线电波
No, but best I can do is have you send out radio waves,
如果车子在附近  就能接收到
and if the car's nearby, it'll pick them up.
就这样做吧
Do it.
乔斯  乔斯  我是XS  希望你能听到
Joss? Joss, it's XS. I hope you can hear me.
你曾经想告诉我
You tried to tell me something earlier.
你试图告诉我
You tried to tell me that you wanted to pay
你想为犯下的罪行负责
for the crimes that you committed.
你说你和你父亲不一样
You said you weren't a criminal like your father.
你让我再给你一次机会
You asked me to give you a second chance,
但是我没有
but I didn't listen.
现在请你再给我一次机会
Now I'm asking you for a second chance.
乔斯  你不是这样的人
Joss, this isn't who you are.
诺拉  车冲着你来了
Nora, the car's headed straight for you.
我什么也没看见
I don't see anything.
诺拉  小心
Nora, look out!
怎么会失控
How the hell did I lose control?
抓住我  感觉会有些怪
Hey, hold on to me. This is gonna feel weird.
至少车在这里
Well, at least we got their wheels.
看她们还有什么能耐
What's left of them.
谢谢你在最后关头救了我
Thanks for the last-minute rescue.
-谢什么  -冰冻了路面
- For the what? - Icing up the road.
我没冻住路面
I didn't ice the road.
什么  那是谁...
What? Who...
还有...
And...
时间到  24小时到了
Time! 24 hours are up.
我和凯特琳都检查过了
Okay, I double-checked with Caitlin,
生物识别器显示
and there doesn't seem to be any unstable dark matter
你身上没有不稳定的暗物质了
in your biometric scans.
太好了
Okay.
天  出来真好
Man, it feels good to be out of there.
我们都很想你  老爸
We definitely missed you, Dad.
抱歉我没能帮上忙
Sorry I haven't been able to help with everything.
有乔斯和拉娅的消息吗
Do we know where Joss and Raya are now?
什么消息都没有
No, we got nothing yet.
但你对乔斯的看法是对的
But you were right about Joss.
她救了我
She saved my life.
如果她没有冻住路面...
If she hadn't iced over the road...
是你对她说的话起作用了
But she did because you connected with her.
就像老爸说的
It's like Dad said,
她只是需要别人的信任
she just needed someone to believe in her.
看来你找到了自己的莱昂纳多·史纳特
Sounds like you found your own Leonard Snart.
现在还不能确定  但我觉得是的
Well, time might prove me wrong, but I think so.
我希望如此
I hope so.
抱歉搞砸了你回来的第一天
I'm sorry I messed up your first day back.
没事的诺拉  时间还长
It's all right, Nora. There's always day two.
-真高兴你回来了  -谢谢
- I'm happy you're back. - Thanks.
能不能帮我找找西斯科
Hey do you wanna help me find Cisco?
我要校正一个外推器
I gotta get this extrapolator thing recalibrated.
我打算去西藏找乔  结果却到了斐济
I went to go see Joe in Tibet, and I ended up in Fiji.
有时候当父母真不容易
Being a parent sure is hard sometimes.
没错
Yeah, it is.
但也弥足珍贵
But there's nothing like it.
好吧  我们不能都消沉
Okay, well, we can't both be the basket case.
我们都是异类
"We're all pretty bizarre.
只是有些人善于隐藏
Some of us are just better at hiding it."
不记得吗  《早餐俱乐部》
Come on, "Breakfast Club"?
我和冰霜杀手
It's one of the only movies
唯一共同喜欢的电影
Killer Frost and I actually agree on.
难道说  她喜欢本德
Let me guess, she's into Bender?
-当然  她非常喜欢他  -说得通
- Totally. She loves him. - Yeah, makes sense.
-能理解  -把衣服穿上
- I'd ship that. - Put that on.
我们要去的地方很冷
It's cold where we're going.
你父亲以前的实验室
Your dad's old lab.
不错
Cool.
凯特琳  为什么带我来这里
Caitlin, why did you bring me here?
尽管我们最后一次见他时
Because despite our last encounter with him,
他培育出了超能力基因者
he did create a meta-gene.
但或许你可以利用他的研究
So I was thinking that you could use his research
做出反转
to do the reverse.
好吧
Um, okay,
如果我什么都不知道的话
don't look now, but if I didn't know any better,
我会以为你在帮我
I'd say this feels a lot like you helping me
制作超能力基因的解药
make a meta-human cure.
我忍不住想你说过的
I couldn't stop thinking about
解药能够带给大家
what you said about how a cure
回归正常生活的机会
would give you a second chance at a normal life.
做为朋友  我没理由反对
No friend would stand in the way of that.
但不反对  和积极地帮我
But there is a difference between you standing in my way
是两码事
and you actively helping me.
我依然觉得这很危险
I still think this is dangerous, but...
但如果我也参与其中  就能有发言权
maybe if I'm involved, we can have some ground rules.
最重要的就是
Like the first and most important,
我们永远不会强迫任何人用解药
we will never, ever force a cure on anyone.
没问题
Okay.
第一准则
Rule number one.
我们不只是制作解药
We're not just here to make a cure.
我们提供选择的机会
We're here to make a choice.
诺拉
Nora.
要么信我  要么不信
You either trust me, or you don't.
不要模棱两可
There's no in-between.
好吧
Fine.
我不相信你
I don't trust you.
但我会给你说服我的机会
But I'm willing to give you the chance to change my mind.
那可能需要一些时间
Well, that might take some time.
而时间  你可能还记得
And time, as you may recall,
不站在我这边
is not on my side.
每一分
Minutes are minutes,
每一秒
seconds are seconds,
没剩下多少了
and there's very few of them left.
我想相信
I want to believe that
你也有善良的一面  斯旺
there is good inside of you somewhere, Thawne.
让我来证明吧
Let me prove there is.
好
Okay.
接下来呢
What's next?
您好  威尔斯博士
Hello, Dr. Wells.
你好  吉迪恩
Hello, Gideon.
我有访问所有资料的权限吗
I have access to all the files?
-有吗  -当然
- Right? - Of course.
您希望查阅哪些资料
Which files would you like me to locate?
我希望你帮我找到
I would like you to locate the files
有关诺拉·韦斯特·艾伦的资料
from Nora West-Allen.
抱歉  威尔斯博士
I'm sorry, Dr. Wells,
诺拉·韦斯特·艾伦
but all entries have been permanently deleted
已经永久删除了所有资料
by Nora West-Allen.